ELOISA DOCTON

eloisadocton@gmail.com | 757.969.8402 | eloisadocton.com | linkedin.com/in/eloisadocton

I SUMMARY

With a plethora of experience in the technology & startup scene, I help companies understand user's behavior & motivations beyond analytics. With a genuine empathetic personality, I translate findings to simple, beautiful & meaningful products.

I SKILLS & TOOLS

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects, Adobe Spark, Photography.

Prototyping: Invision App, Marvel App, & Sketch.

User Experience: Wireframes, User Flows, User Research, UI Kits & Patterns.

Web Development: HTML, CSS/Sass, Jquery & CMS platforms like WordPress, Squarespace & Google.

Marketing: Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, MarketingCloud, Email & Social Media.

Languages: Spanish & English.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp: The Iron Yard, 2017, UI Design

College: Instituto de Tecnologia Industrial Rodolfo Loero Arismendi, 1996-1999, Tourism

Apprenticeship: Atelier de Artes Alezard, 1994-1995, Fashion Design

EXPERIENCE

MARCH 2018 - PRESENT

WeaveUp, Web Content Manager

- Implement social media & content for all of WeaveUp's marketing projects.
- Collaborate with B2B clients to implement content & products for their platforms.
- Cultivate & embody WeaveUp's brand voice.

MARCH 2017 - MARCH 2018

Divi Resorts, Design Manager

- Lead a team of designers through all web-development and design projects including creative collateral like landing pages, email design print projects & user experience.
- Utilize Google and Adobe Analytics to design website improvements. Today, Divi's website sessions have increased 94% & bounce rates have decreased 61% due to these efforts.
- Disciplines include creative direction, branding, front-end development, digital strategy, user interface and responsive design.

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JULY 2016

Spoonflower, Buyer, 2015-2016

- Involved in product development, user testing & monitoring.
- Created a tracking system for product lifecycle and inventory control for two international factories.
- Advised partners on product positioning, pricing & timelines.
- Negotiated an average savings of 5% on blanket orders.

Sr. Customer Service Advocate, 2014-2015

- My role was the first line of communication between customers and the company. Using feedback & findings to make improvement recommendations.
- Handled design, website & order issues by collaborating between various teams.
- In charge of Spoonflower's factory tours and assisted with events.
- Created informational material and blog posts for the marketing team.

Operations Team Member, 2013-2014

Assisted with order fulfillment, from inspecting, cutting fabric, sublimating & shipping.

I FREELANCE

My portfolio includes Illustrations, Graphic Design & Web Design created for:

Cinnamon Joe Studios: UK-Based Art Company that represents artists worldwide in shows such as Surtex and Blueprint. My designs have been sold and used by companies such as JoAnn's Fabrics. Justice, Target & Jelly the Pug, among others.

Timeless Treasures: New York-Based Textile Company that specializes in guilt-weight materials sold worldwide.

Mami Jami: San Francisco-Based baby-products startup. Created logos & branding materials. **Right Comply:** San Francisco-Based HR-products startup. Designed website & branding materials.

Case-Mate: Atlanta-Based phone cases & accessories company. Licensed designs.

I COMMUNITY

Dribbble: Triangle Meetup Organizer

Triangle UXPA: Member

AIGA: Member

Women Who Code: Member Girl Develop It: Volunteer

Durham Women in Tech: Member

Chik-Teck: Member

I VOLUNTEERING

Fundraising Chair: Fuguay Varina High School Band Booster

Fvbb.org Webmaster, Web Designer & Graphics: Fuguay Varina High School Band Booster

Event Volunteer: Girl Develop It Event Volunteer: Open Source 101

I COLLABORATIONS

Spoonflower: Textile design free courses in-person & online from 2013 - 2016.

The Iron Yard: Illustration, design, logo creation free classes for the general public & students in 2017.

| SIDE-GIGS

Etsy Shop: Mums n Posies, custom-designed cloth dolls & accessories www.mumsnposies.com

Spoonflower Shop: Won 3 design challenges, 1 employee design challenge & top-10 designer countless

times.

WeaveUp Shop: https://app.weaveup.com/profile/4224

I ENHANCEMENT COURSES

App-Building with Salesforce: 2017, Girl Develop It.

Service Design: 2017, Raleigh Service Jam. GitHub 101: 2017, Open Source 101, The Iron Yard.